Erin Bleiweiss

713-829-4800

erinbleiweiss@gmail.com

Austin, TX

erinbleiweiss.com

github.com/erinbleiweiss

in linkedin.com/in/erinbleiweiss

Senior software engineer with eight years of experience in full-stack app development emphasizing cybersecurity and IoT. Expert in Go, Python, Swift, and Javascript frontend frameworks. Creative, passionate, and versatile collaborator with a knack for problem-solving and an eye for design. Advocate for documentation, user experience, and sustainable development practices.

Experience

runZero

Sr. Security Research Engineer June 2022–April 2023

- Improved asset fingerprinting across Go-based network discovery product, adding device detection for hundreds of products
- Incorporated new device and software detection based on customer feedback
- Enhanced UI by implementing custom alerts, templates, and queries using Vue.js
- Provided technical support to customers, resolving issues and addressing bugs

Rapid7

Software Engineer II February 2019–June 2022

Software Engineer I July 2018–February 2019

- Full-stack Go web development for creation of a new crowdsourced vulnerability assessment and discussion forum (attackerkb.com)
- Architected Terraform cloud infrastructure, deployment, and web-based scoreboard for yearly Metasploit community Capture The Flag event with 1,000+ users
- Built and maintained REST API in Ruby for Metasploit Framework web service
- Wrote community-oriented blog posts capturing release highlights for Metasploit Framework

Jackrabbit Mobile

iOS and Web Developer September 2016-June 2018

- Developed mobile apps (Swift), API and backend services (Python/AWS), and web apps (Angular 2/Typescript)
- Communicated technical information and demonstrated features to clients
- Coordinated with third-party hardware teams for IoT project feature development
- Advised sales team with scoping and development estimates for prospective clients
- Created and maintained technical documentation for client work

Ihiji (acquired by Control4)

Web Application Developer May 2015-May 2016

- Built and maintained web applications in PHP with Python backend
- Integrated third party IP-enabled devices for monitoring and management
- Enhanced user-facing portal with new metrics and UI improvements
- Modernized email notifications system to utilize new API

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, Go, Ruby, SQL, Swift, Java, PHP, HTML, CSS, JS

Frontend Web: npm, node, yarn, SASS, Webpack, jQuery, Bootstrap, Angular, Typescript, Vue, Handlebars, Flask,

Backend/Deployment: AWS, Terraform, Heroku, Firebase, Jenkins, Docker

Education

Bachelor of Arts, Plan II Honors Minor, Computer Science

The University of Texas at Austin *May 2016*

 Plan II is an Interdisciplinary honors program encouraging specialization and culminating in a capstone thesis. As my thesis project, I independently designed and developed an experimental mobile game for iOS, which was published in the App Store.